Guide to the Anne Morrow Lindbergh Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1918-1978; Accession 2002-M-079
  - Correspondence
    - Family
      - Transcripts-carbons, 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Anne Morrow Lindbergh to Charles A. Lindbergh, transcripts-carbons, 1943-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Morrow, Dwight W. (regarding), 1953-1960 (Box 1, Folder 6a)
    - Outgoing
      - Trip to Europe, transcripts-carbons, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8-11)
    - From readers regarding "Heron & the Astronaut," Life article, 1969 February 27-March 27 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - Christmas cards
      - 1973 November 2-1974 January 14 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
      - 1974 November-[1974], undated (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - Public opinion mail (C mail)
      - 1960-1974 March (Box 3, Folder 4-7)
      - 1974 April-July (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
      - 1974 August -December (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
      - [1974] (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
      - 1975 January-June (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
      - 1975 July-Dec, [1975] (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
      - Clippings, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Gifts from the Sea, 1975 January-September (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Letters from Unknowns
        - 1975 January-February (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - 1975 April-1975 undated (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
      - 1976 January-April 9 (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
      - 1976 April 10-July 8 (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
      - 1976 July 10-November (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
      - 1976 December-1977 (Box 12, Folder 1-9)
      - 1978 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Writings
    - Diaries, typescripts
      - 1919 January-1928 October (Box 13, Folder 2-11)
        Copy 3
      - 1922-1942 (Box 13, Folder 12)
        Anne Morrow Lindbergh Cuts, originals
      - 1939 June 20-1941 June 22 (Box 13, Folder 13-16)
      - 1941 November 6-1942 July 17 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
        Copy 1-3
      - 1942 December-1943 April (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
        Journal-Copy 1 and 3
      - 1943 April 14-September 3 (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
        Copy 1-2
      - 1943 September 3-1944 January 30 (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
      - 1944 January-October (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
      - 1944 October 27-1946 October 22 (Box 15, Folder 4)
        Copy 1
      - 1947 January 5-July 31 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - 1970, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
        Pages copied
    - Poems, Copy 3, 1922-1941 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "Earth Shine"
      - Page proofs, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Publishers MS, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Galley, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Little Blue Book" (notebook), Circa 1944-circa 1946 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - "Memories of Falaise," Copy 1, 1973 October (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - "Red Notebook," Copy 3 (notebook), 1940 October-1942 winter (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Yellow Notebook," Copy 3 (notebook), 1934-1940 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Estate of Elizabeth Cutter Morrow
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1955-1959 February 25 (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
      - Brooklyn Museum donation, 1955 November 9-1956 December 8 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - Casa Mañana, 1955 March 16-1958 March 31 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - Distributions to Smith and Amherst, 1955 March 8-1959 March 3 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Distributions to Smith, Amherst and Elisabeth Morrow School, 1955-1957 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Inauguration of Stanley King, President, Amherst College, 1932 September 12-November 11 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - North Haven, Maine property, 1957 March 11-1958 March 5 (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
    - Financial
      - Correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Estate tax return, Federal, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Statements and correspondence, J. P. Morgan, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Statements and correspondence, J. P. Morgan, 1955-1958 April 30 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - Legal
      - Affidavits and correspondence, 1956 March 8-1957 July 10 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Appraisal, personal property, Next Day Hill, 1955 January 23 (Box 18, Folder 4-6)
      - Deeds
        - Agreements and Letters Testamentary, 1955 February 3-September 20, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
        - Appraisal and correspondence, North Haven, Maine property, 1955 April-1956 October 17 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Distribution Lists
        - Aldrich, Amey, Undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
        - Chilton, Constance, Undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
        - Cutter, Annie, Undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
        - Morrow, Dwight, and children, Undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
        - Smith, Amherst, and Elisabeth Morrow School, Undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
        - Yates, Edith, Undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
        - Next Day Hill (early), Circa 1955? (Box 19, Folder 8)
        - Correspondence, 1955 March 3-1956 December 19 (Box 19, Folder 9)
        - Shipping invoices and waybills, AML, 1955 April 12-June 2 (Box 19, Folder 10)
        - Shipping estimate, Morgan, Constance Morrow, 1955 March 30, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Estate tax return, New York, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Executor's accounting, final, 1958 June (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Inheritance tax return, New Jersey, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Inventory of Casa Mañana, Mexico, 1956 January 16-March 12, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Last will and testament (typeset), 1955 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Parke-Benet Galleries, inventory of items sent to, Undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Possible gifts, "silver," taken to Darien, Anne Morrow Lindbergh, Undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Shipping invoices and waybills to Smith College and Amherst College, Undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Notices of motion and settlement, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Receipt and release, trust for Anne S. Lindbergh, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Addendum to "List of Certain Gifts Made by Charles and Anne Lindbergh," second carbon, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - St. Augustine prayer for Anne Morrow Lindbergh's funeral, second carbon, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Memorabilia
    - Helmet, flying, Anne Morrow Lindbergh's, Circa 1930s (Box 21)
    - Goggles, flying, Anne Morrow Lindbergh's, Circa 1930s (Box 21)
- Additional material, 1924-1999; Accession 2004-M-010
  The accession is arranged in five sections: Correspondence from friends and acquaintenances, Family correspondence, Legal correspondence, General correspondence, and Housekeeping.
  - Correspondence from friends and acquaintenances
    - Aldrich, Amey, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alvarez, Thelma, 1986 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ames, Amyas, 1976 June (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ames, Amyas and Evelyn, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ames, Evelyn, 1976 May 18, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Anderson, Gov. [Elmer L.], 1977 October 10 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Barron, Carol, 1986 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bassage, Anne, 1988 August 23, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Berns, Cathy, 1987 June 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Birkett, William, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bueler, Gladys, 1979 January 8-February 5 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Burk, _____, 1974 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Cate, Garth, 1958 June 20-30 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Christen, Eliette, 1976-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Cochard, Vincent, 1990 July 3 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Collins, Linda, 1998 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Curtiss, Mina (Kirstein), 1964 April 17, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Davidoff, Ida, 1986 September 21 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Delattre, Yvonne, 1959-1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Dillingham, Charlie, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Eisenhower, Julie, 1976 June 3-22 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Eissler, Dr. Ruth S., 1979-1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Explorer Post, 1985 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Fergussen, Joanne, 1989 October 17, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Ferguson, Joanne and Tom, 1997 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Franklin, Helena, 1973 October 18, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Fredette, R. H., 1988 December 19 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Godden, Rumer, 1961 December (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Graff, René, 1963 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Gray, Nancy Hunter, 1979 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Gray, Virginia, 1976 April 5-27 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Grierson, "Brownie", Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Grierson, John, 1976 May 28-1977 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Growald, Eileen R., 1987 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Guillermin, Jean-Claude, 1981 February 7 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Hamel, Sharlene, 1987 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Harris, Louisa, 1976-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Haskins, Sylvia, 1976 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Hildt, Margaret, 1987 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Johnson, Jeanne, 1986 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Jones, Soonie, Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Judson, Sylvia, 1976 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Kennedy, Jacqueline, 1962 May 16 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Knobel, Elsie, 1986 November 12 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Knollenberg, Mary, 1979 December 22 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Konzett, Farn and Steiger, Jerry, 1976 May 16 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Lamont, Corliss, 1964-1976 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Lewis, Dotsy, 1976 May 3-June 21 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Lloyd, Jim, 1985 August 6-17 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Lowre, Donna, 1999 September 15 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Mathias, Blanche, 1973 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Maxwell, Emmy, Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Maxwell, Emmy and Bill, Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - McCullough, David, 1986 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - McEwan, Ruth Bell, 1985 February 26 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - McGavin, Ann, 1979 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Meissinger, Lilli and Vincent, Gertrude, 1972-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Miller, Mrs., Undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Minke, Gisela, 1971 November 3-1972 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Mitchell, Stephen, 1972 June 2-November 25 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Moreillon, Eglantine, 1971-1987 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Morgran, Barbara, 1986 October 14 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Munroe, Vernon, 1987 March 16 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Musser, Laura Jane, 1987 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Newton, Ellie, 1987 April 19, undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Newton, Ellie and James D. "Jim", 1985-1993, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Newton, James D. "Jim", 1976-1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Norton, Katherine, Undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Obermeier, Nesta, 1973-1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
      Letter from "Coley," [Leonard Cole] to Nesta Obermeier (postmarked Aug 11, 1973) includes a photograph of Noel Coward taken the day before he died.
    - Oldrin, John, 1968 July 30-August 6 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Origo, Iris, 1971 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Orton, Vest, 1973 January 21 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Pagenhardt, Heidi, 1976 February 10 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Pearson, Dr. Bror F., 1979 July 20-September 12 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Pfeiffer, Mara, 1986 September 24-1987 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Prosser, Anna Fay, Undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Pryor, Karen, 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Pryor, Mary Tay and Sam, 1975 December 23 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Randolph, Francis, 1963 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Regina Laudis Monastery, 1974-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Robbins, Lynne, 1986 December 26 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Rossen, Hazel, 1997 December 22 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Saunders, Jean, 1979 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Scandrett, Mary, 1972 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Schiff, Judith, 1986 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Seld, Dr. D., 1982 October 2-November 7 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Shannon, Mary, 1976-1987 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Stearman, Patty, 1997 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Steindl-Rast, M. David, 1984 June 25-November 4 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Stirling, Monica, 1973-1982 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Stirling, Monica, Undated (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Strudwick Mary, 1987 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Swanson, Minnie (Wilhemina), 1979-1987 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Taquey, Kitty, 1979 July 18 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Tinsman, Bea, 1976 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Trout, Bobbi, 1999 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Valentine, Alan, 1963 December 24 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Valentine, Lucia, 1967-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Valentine, Lucia and Alan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Waldburger, Anne, 1979 July 22-August 12 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Wolff, Helen, 1967-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Wood, Mrs. Willis Delano, Undated (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Wriggins, Sally, 1987 June 30-August 9 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - _____, Adelaide, 1952 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - _____, Laura, Undated (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - _____, Mary ("Nelly"), 1970 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - _____, Nancy, Undated (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - _____, Polly, 1984 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Unidentified, 1944 October 17, undated (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Family correspondence
    - Lindbergh, Barbara, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - Lindbergh, Barbara and Jon, 1979 December 29 (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - Lindbergh, Charles Augustus, 1965 June 25 (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - Lindbergh, Connie, 1977 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - Lindbergh, Jon See also: Lindbergh, Barbara and Jon, 1982 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - Lindbergh, Kristine, 1984 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - Lindbergh, Scott, 1978-1988 (Box 1, Folder 116)
    - Morrow, Elizabeth Cutter, 1924 May 29-June 1 (Box 1, Folder 117)
    - Morrow, Nancy, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - Legal correspondence
    - Deeds to Burial Plots (Hawaii), 1974 August 14 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Etude Carrard & Paschoud re: Swiss taxes, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General correspondence
    - Form letters, 1960 September 15-1961 November 15 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Invitations to speak/attend, 1962-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Reader, letter from, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Requests to publish, 1966-circa 1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Smith College collection, requests for access, 1979 January 11-19 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Housekeeping
    - Correspondence, 1967, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Calendars, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Instructions and correspondence, 1963-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Lists, books sent, 1964-1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, lists, notes and receipts, 1964-1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Additional material, 1977-1982; Accession 2004-M-020
  - Letters to Dr. William A. Atchley concerning his father, Dr. Dana Winslow Atchley, 1977 Apr, 1982 July 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1967-1997; Accession 2007-M-034; 0.25
  The addition is arranged alphabetically by title.
  This addition consists of Japanese editions of writings by Anne Morrow Lindbergh.
  - Bring Me a Unicorn, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Gift from the Sea, 1967, [1975?] (Box 1)
    Two copies hardcover; one paperback
  - Hour of Gold, Hour of Lead, 1997 (Box 1)